Guide to the Edgar Hockley Collection
Yale Center for British Art, Rare Books and Manuscripts
- Designs by Era, Series III; Hockley, Edgar, 1860-1938
  - Victorian (male & female): drawing of a male and a female, circa 1886-1897; 1 drawing: graphite; 23.5 x 18.5 cm (Box 3, Folder 22a)
    Includes the names of the characters in the drawing: "Edith" and possibly "Larkin."
- Designs by Subject, Series IV; Hockley, Edgar, 1860-1938
  - Acrobats (female): drawings of a female figure in a dress, circa 1886-1897; 3 drawings on 1 sheet: graphite; 11 x 6 cm (Box 4, Folder 1a)
    Includes a brief note on the color of the dress.
  - Acrobats (female): drawings of a female on a horse and in a dress, circa 1886-1897; 4 drawings on 1 sheet: graphite; 11 x 18 cm (Box 4, Folder 1b)
  - Acrobats (female): drawings of female trapeze artists, circa 1886-1897; 19 drawings on 1 sheet: graphite; 11 x 18 cm (Box 4, Folder 1c)
    Nineteen small drawings depict various stages of female trapeze act.
  - Acrobats (female): drawing of two trapeze artists connected by a rope, circa 1886-1897; 1 drawing: graphite; 18 x 11 cm (Box 4, Folder 1(d))
  - Acrobats (female): drawings of two acrobats on a tightrope, circa 1886-1897; 2 drawings on 1 sheet: graphite; 11 x 18 cm (Box 4, Folder 1e)
    Larger drawing depicts two tightrope walkers. Smaller drawing depicts a single tightrope walker with a leg lifted.
  - Acrobats (female): drawings of tightrope walkers in various positions, circa 1886-1897; 6 drawings on 1 sheet: graphite; 11 x 18 cm (Box 4, Folder 1(f))
    Drawings depict female tightrope walkers in various stages of action.
  - Acrobats (female): drawing of a tightrope walker in a leotard, circa 1886-1897; 1 drawing: graphite; 11 x 6 cm (Box 4, Folder 1g)
  - Acrobats (female): drawings of a female holding a staff, from behind, and her patella, circa 1886-1897; 3 drawings on 1 sheet: graphite; 11 x 18 cm (Box 2, Folder 1h)
    Includes detail and color notes for her stomach, thighs, patella, etc.
  - Court jesters: drawing of a jester on a throne with a king, circa 1886-1897; 1 drawing: graphite; 11 x 18 cm (Box 4, Folder 2a)
  - Court jesters: drawings of a jester and steps, circa 1886-1897; 5 drawings on 1 sheet: graphite; 18 x 11 cm (Box 4, Folder 2b)
    Includes detail and color notes for the jester's costume, some steps, and a balcony.
  - Court jesters: drawing of a jester and a reclining figure in an interior, circa 1886-1897; 1 drawing: graphite; 13 x 20 cm (Box 4, Folder 2c)
  - Court jesters: drawings of a jester and two males, circa 1886-1897; 2 drawings on 1 sheet: graphite; 13 x 20 cm (Box 4, Folder 2(d))
    Includes detail and color notes for the tunic, belt, hose, boots, satchel, etc.
    Pen and ink drawings; Costume design drawings; Set design drawings
  - Court jesters: drawing of a jester and three females, circa 1886-1897; 2 drawings on 1 sheet: gouache over pen and ink; 14 x 11 cm (Box 4, Folder 2e)
    Pen and ink drawings; Gouaches; Costume design drawings
  - Fairies: drawings of fairies in various positions, circa 1886-1897; 7 drawings on 1 sheet: graphite; 11 x 17 cm (Box 4, Folder 3a)
    Reverse side of the sheet contains two faint beginnings of drawings.
  - Fairies: drawings of fairies and various figures dancing, circa 1886-1897; 7 drawings on 1 sheet: graphite; 11.5 x 18 cm (Box 4, Folder 3b)
    Includes detail and color notes for the hose, tunic, etc.
  - Figure drawing: drawings of a female from the back, circa 1886-1897; 2 drawings on 1 sheet: graphite; 23.5 x 18.5 cm (Box 4, Folder 4a)
    Includes notes on drawing the patella and the leg.
    Graphite drawings; Female figure drawings
  - Figure drawing: drawings of female bathers on the beach, circa 1886-1897; 6 drawings on 1 sheet: graphite; 23.5 x 18.5 cm (Box 4, Folder 4b)
    Includes notes on drawing the patella, the leg, and the arm.
    Female figure drawings; Graphite drawings
  - Figure drawing: drawing of a female kneeling, circa 1886-1897; 1 drawing: graphite; 7 x 4.5 cm (Box 4, Folder 4c)
  - Figure drawing: drawings of a female from three perspectives, circa 1886-1897; 3 drawings on 1 sheet: graphite; 10.5 x 11 cm (Box 4, Folder 4(d))
    Sheet has a hole torn in the middle.
  - Figure drawing: drawings of a female torso from three perspectives, circa 1886-1897; 3 drawings on 1 sheet: graphite; 18 x 11 cm (Box 4, Folder 4e)
  - Figure drawing: drawings of a female with arms outstretched, circa 1886-1897; 2 drawings on 1 sheet: graphite; 18 x 13 cm (Box 4, Folder 4(f))
  - Figure drawing: drawing of a female from the left side, circa 1886-1897; 1 drawing: graphite; 11 x 4.5 cm (Box 4, Folder 4g)
  - Furniture: drawings of a King's chair, table and seat, circa 1886-1897; 2 drawings on 1 sheet: graphite; 13.5 x 11 cm (Box 4, Folder 5a)
    Includes detail and color notes.
    Graphite drawings; Set design drawings
  - Furniture: drawings of a screen, a cabinet, a chair, and a settee, circa 1886-1897; 2 drawings on 1 sheet: graphite; 11 x 18 cm (Box 4, Folder 5b)
    Includes detail and color notes for the furniture, drapery, and walls.
  - Galateia: drawing of Galateia with Akis riding on the back of a sea nymph, circa 1886-1897; 1 drawing: graphite; 10.5 x 12 cm (Box 2, Folder 6a)
  - Galateia: drawing of Galateia with a bearded male, circa 1886-1897; 1 drawing: graphite; 10 x 7 cm (Box 2, Folder 6b)
  - Galateia: drawing of Galateia from the left side, circa 1886-1897; 1 drawing: graphite; 18 x 11 cm (Box 2, Folder 6c)
  - Galateia: drawing of Galateia with a cape and Akis riding on the back of a sea nymph, circa 1886-1897; 1 drawing: graphite; 15 x 12 cm (Box 4, Folder 6(d))
  - Galateia: drawing of Galateia and an arm, circa 1886-1897; 1 drawing: graphite; 16 x 8 cm (Box 4, Folder 6e)
  - Galateia: drawing of Galateia kneeling, circa 1886-1897; 1 drawing: graphite; 11 x 18 cm (Box 4, Folder 6(f))
  - Galateia: drawing of Galateia from behind, circa 1886-1897; 1 drawing: graphite; 11 x 7.5 cm (Box 4, Folder 6g)
  - Galateia: drawing of legs with patella detail, circa 1886-1897; 1 drawing: graphite; 9 x 7 cm (Box 4, Folder 6h)
    Includes detail notes for the patella and legs.
  - Jewelry: drawings of three jeweled accessories, circa 1886-1897; 3 drawings on 1 sheet: graphite; 7.5 x 10 cm (Box 4, Folder 7a)
    Includes a brief detail note explaining the placement of diamonds upon the lace in one of the drawings.
  - Orientalism: drawings of a male with a plumed helmet and a male on a horse, circa 1886-1897; 3 drawings on 1 sheet: graphite; 11 x 18 cm (Box 4, Folder 8a)
    Includes detail and color notes for the horseman's hat, cloak, hose, etc.
  - Orientalism: drawings of a female with a headdress on a horse, circa 1886-1897; 4 drawings on 1 sheet: graphite; 11 x 18 cm (Box 4, Folder 8b)
    Includes detail and color notes for the headdress, skirt, belt, sleeves, etc.
  - Orientalism: drawing of horsemen with turbans attacking, circa 1886-1897; 1 drawing: graphite; 5 x 18 cm (Box 4, Folder 8c)
  - Orientalism: drawing of two females in skirts, circa 1886-1897; 2 drawings on 1 sheet: graphite; 23.5 x 18.5 cm (Box 4, Folder 8(d))
    Includes detail and color notes for the skirts, headdress, shawl, hose, etc. One note states: "Dress more scarlet orange than Ellen Terry Merry Wives of Windsor dress which was more salmon."
  - Orientalism: drawings of a male wearing a fez, and a camel, and a lion, circa 1886-1897; 6 drawings on 1 sheet: graphite; 11 x 18 cm (Box 4, Folder 8e)
    Includes detail and color notes for the jacket, knickers, belt, hat, etc.
  - Orientalism: drawings of a male standing on the backs of two horses and sitting, circa 1886-1897; 6 drawings on 1 sheet: graphite; 11 x 18 cm (Box 4, Folder 8(f))
    Includes detail and color notes for the tunic, cloak, tunic, trousers, etc.
  - Religious: drawing of a scene including clergy, circa 1886-1897; 1 drawing: graphite; 11 x 18 cm (Box 4, Folder 9a)
  - Religious: drawing of two males wearing mitres, circa 1886-1897; 1 drawing: graphite; 11 x 9.5 cm (Box 4, Folder 9b)
  - Religious: drawing of a procession with a male carrying a cross, circa 1886-1897; 1 drawing: graphite and gouache; 10.5 x 18 cm (Box 4, Folder 9c)
    Includes detail and color notes for the male's hood, cord, etc. Drawing is on a blue-grey sheet.
    Set design drawings; Graphite drawings; Costume design drawings; Gouaches
  - Religious: drawing of two males wearing mitres and a queen on a throne, circa 1886-1897; 1 drawing: graphite; 11 x 18 cm (Box 4, Folder 9(d))
    Includes brief detail and color notes.
  - Religious: drawings of a male wearing a mitre on stage, a queen on a throne, and a broken tree, circa 1886-1897; 2 drawings on 1 sheet: graphite; 18 x 11.5 cm (Box 4, Folder 9e)
    Includes detail and color notes for panels on the theater side walls, the table, a dress, and a bucolic scene.
  - Religious: drawings of a Dutch female, a male clergy member, and three males, circa 1886-1897; 3 drawings on 1 sheet: graphite; 11.5 x 18 cm (Box 4, Folder 9(f))
    Includes detail and color notes for the cap, dress, sabots, vestments, wig, knickers, etc. Notes mention "David" and "Abbe."
  - Scene: drawing of two females and an interior, circa 1886-1897; 1 drawing: watercolor over graphite; 10 x 16 cm (Box 4, Folder 10a)
    The verso is an envelope mailed from the Bank of England to "Edgar HOCKLEY, Esq., 14, Prospect Road, Markhouse Road, WALTHAMSTOW, Essex." The envelope bears a postage mark from London. The British Postal Museum and Archive was contacted to ascertain the date of the postmark. The rates provided suggest the postmark dates between approximately 1870 and 1918.
    Costume design drawings; Graphite drawings; Set design drawings; Watercolors
  - Scene: drawing of a night scene including a column, circa 1886-1897; 1 drawing: watercolor over graphite; 18 x 11 cm (Box 4, Folder 10b)
    Drawing (3.5 x 7.5) is affixed to the larger sheet. Includes detail and color notes for the stone, the column, stray, etc.
    Graphite drawings; Costume design drawings; Set design drawings; Watercolors
  - Scenery: drawing of a vista beyond a row of columns, circa 1886-1897; 1 drawing: graphite; 18 x 11 cm (Box 4, Folder 11a)
    Includes detail and color notes for the sky, mountains, hills, curtains, etc.
  - Scenery: drawing of a room with stairs, chairs and a mural, circa 1886-1897; 1 drawing: graphite; 13 x 20 cm (Box 4, Folder 11b)
  - Scenery: drawings of a rotunda and a male with an extended arm, circa 1886-1897; 2 drawings on 1 sheet: graphite; 30 x 20.5 cm (Box 4, Folder 11c)
    Two smaller sheets (13 x 20 cm and 13 x 19 cm) of red paper ruled with blue lines are affixed to the larger sheet. Includes detail and color notes for the male costume.
  - Unidentified characters (female): drawings of females in Nordic, Spanish, and Dutch costumes, circa 1886-1897; 10 drawings on 1 sheet: graphite; 23.5 x 19 cm (Box 4, Folder 12a)
    Includes detail and color notes for five of the drawings.
  - Unidentified characters (female): drawings of female wearing jewels on her head, shoulder, and breast, circa 1886-1897; 1 drawing: graphite; 17.5 x 11.5 cm (Box 4, Folder 12b)
  - Unidentified characters (female): drawings of females in Nordic costume and wearing a large brimmed hat, circa 1886-1897; 3 drawings on 1 sheet: graphite; 8.5 x 12 cm (Box 4, Folder 12c)
    Includes detail and color notes for the trousers, veil, etc. The sheet was once an envelope, the reserve side of which bears a Brighton postmark from July 20. The addressee is as follows: "Mr. Hockley, 14 Prospect Rd., Markhouse Road, Walthamstow, Essex."
  - Unidentified characters (female): drawing of a female in an indigo dress, circa 1886-1897; 1 drawing: pen and ink; 20 x 13 cm (Box 4, Folder 12d)
    Includes detail and color notes for the headdress, jewel, dress, etc.
    Pen and ink drawings; Costume design drawings
  - Unidentified characters (female): drawing of a female in a dress with an apron, circa 1886-1897; 1 drawing: pen and ink; 11.5 x 4.5 cm (Box 4, Folder 12e)
  - Unidentified characters (female): drawing of a female holding a sword, circa 1886-1897; 1 drawing: graphite; 11 x 11 cm (Box 4, Folder 12(f))
    Includes detail and color notes for the hair, waistcoat, sleeve, apron, hose, etc.
  - Unidentified characters (female): drawing of a female holding a sphere, circa 1886-1897; 1 drawing: graphite; 12 x 7 cm (Box 4, Folder 12g)
  - Unidentified characters (male): drawing of a male in armor, circa 1886-1897; 1 drawing: graphite; 18 x 11 cm (Box 4, Folder 13a)
    Includes detail and color notes for the spear and armor.
  - Unidentified characters (male): drawing of a male in a robe with star of David and pointed helmet, circa 1886-1897; 1 drawing: graphite; 15 x 13 cm (Box 4, Folder 13b)
    Includes color note for the helmet.
  - Unidentified characters (male): drawings of a male in a robe with star of David, front and rear view, circa 1886-1897; 2 drawings on 1 sheet: graphite; 13 x 20 cm (Box 4, Folder 13c)
    Includes color and detail notes for the cap, tunic, cape, sword, etc.
  - Unidentified characters (male): drawings of a Lieutenant with a sword and shield, circa 1886-1897; 4 drawings on 1 sheet: graphite; 12 x 19 cm (Box 4, Folder 13d)
    Includes color and detail notes for the cloak, helmet, tunic, hair, etc.
  - Unidentified characters (male): drawing of a portly male reading on a chair, circa 1886-1897; 1 drawing: graphite; 7 x 10 cm (Box 4, Folder 13e)
  - Unidentified characters (male): drawings of a male with a moustache and sword, circa 1886-1897; 3 drawings on 1 sheet: graphite; 11 x 18 cm (Box 4, Folder 13(f))
    Includes detail and color notes for the hair, moustache, tunic, hose, etc.
  - Unidentified characters (male): drawings of a male with hand aloft near shrub, circa 1886-1897; 3 drawings on 1 sheet: graphite; 11 x 17 cm (Box 4, Folder 13d)
    Includes detail and color notes for the hose, cloak, tunic, and shrub.
  - Unidentified characters (male): drawing of a male with beard and cloak, circa 1886-1897; 1 drawing: graphite; 18 x 11 cm (Box 4, Folder 13e)
    Includes detail and color notes for the hair, tunic, cloak, and hose. Also mentions that the character is "always smiling" and has a "small thin ragged beard."
  - Unidentified characters (male & female): drawings of a female beside a male on a throne, a female from behind, and a female being whipped, circa 1886-1897; 3 drawings on 1 sheet: graphite; 23.5 x 18.5 cm (Box 4, Folder 14a)
  - Unidentified characters (male & female): drawing of a male raising his hand as a female kneels, circa 1886-1897; 1 drawing: graphite; 18 x 11.5 cm (Box 4, Folder 14b)
    Includes the caption: "Tell your father there are plenty of houses to let now." A note on the bottom of the drawing states: "Drawing of Fratella correct to Augustus Caesar. B Museum."
  - Unidentified characters (male & female): drawings of a male in a helmet and a female in a dress, circa 1886-1897; 2 drawings on 1 sheet: graphite; 11 x 18 cm (Box 4, Folder 14c)
    Includes detail and color notes for the helmet, tunic, cloak, tassels, dress, etc. The verso of the sheet has the note: "grand."
  - Unidentified characters (male & female): drawings of a male and a female in various positions, circa 1886-1897; 6 drawings on 1 sheet: graphite; 11 x 18 cm (Box 4, Folder 14d)
  - Unidentified characters (male & female): drawing of males reclining while females dance, circa 1886-1897; 1 drawing: graphite; 13 x 20 cm (Box 4, Folder 14e)
    Includes a note on the design of the fences in the scene.
  - Works by Danish Painters exhibit: drawing of the 1907 exhibition at Guildhall, 1 drawing (2 leaves): graphite; 13 x 20 and 17 x 11 cm (Box 4, Folder 15a)
    The first leaf depicts one wall, perhaps displaying Danish decorative art. The second leaf, otherwise blank, is titled "Danish Exhibition, Guild Hall, 1907."
    Graphite drawings; Guildhall (London, England)